Gaspare Frazzitta

Lead Product UI/UX Designer

+44 (0)751 0525438 me@gasparefrazzitta.com London

Portfolio www.gasparefrazzitta.com

Professional profile

About me

UX/UI Product designer with many years of experience on delivering intuitive products focused around users and business needs, all the way through best in class user interfaces designs for iOS, Android apps and web.

Skills and programs

UI: Expert in Figma, Adobe CC Suite, Motion design (AE, Principle, Invision).

UX: Miro, Whimsical, FigJam, Usertesting.com. Expert in collaborating with researches, run competitors researches and analysis, plan and run user interviews, quantitative surveys, wireframing and prototyping. I also enjoy facilitating workshops & design sprints.

Experience

2020 - today

Lead Product designer at Zego

Zego is a commercial motor insurance that combines best in class tech with sophisticated data sources to offer insurance product that save business and customers time and money. I lead the product design of our Sense apps (150M revenue 2021) and line manage 2 product designers. I work closely with my team, UX Researchers, Product Managers, Engineers and Stakeholders to deliver the best in class products that brings value to our customers and business.

2014-2020

Lead Product designer at TouchNote (former Senior Product Designer)

I led the Product Design team across multi channels and platforms [iOS, Android, Web], creative direction on physical products and digital visual aesthetics, motion design and photography. I contributed to the conceptualisation, production and release of the membership model which counts over 150000 members, many in-app successful features, 15 million TouchNote cards sent worldwide, many awards such as the Good Web Guide's App of the Year 2018, Financial Times Tech 100 Europe and numerous accolades on the Apple AppStore and Google PlayStore

2014

Senior Product Designer at Wayra

Wayra UK is a world-leading start-up accelerator programme. Since 2012, it has helped more than 160 British and Irish start-ups take their businesses to the next level, helping them raise over \$150m in third-party funding. My role was to define the brand guidelines as well as design the website and iOS app for a startup called Busk.

Awards

Zego Fastest-growing tech company in the UK - The Deloitte Tech

Top 50 - 11th position - 2021

TouchNote Major Influencer Campaign - The Major Players 2018 TouchNote Studio team

Technology Fast 50 Deloitte UK, Everline future 50 2016, BMA platinum nominee

Clippy Notes 3rd prize app at Microsoft UK, Publish 2015 in London.

House Finder Most innovative app from AppCampus.fi at MWC Barcelona 2015

More about me

Education 2017 - Media Training London, UK

Motion Design | After Effects CC.

2016 - General Assembly London School, UK

User Experience design campus.

2010 - 2013 Academy of Fine Arts, Florence, Italy

Bachelor of Arts: Graphic Design

Languages Italian (native), English, Spanish (basic).

HobbiesI love cooking and I'm a tea addicted. I also enjoy cycling and spend my spare time outdoors.

I love social media, i made my cat a "instagram wannabe influencer" (@MrChonkes). I also have a huge passion for history, collecting coins, Interior Design and everything about the

80s and 90s.



